all right hello welcome Lisa and Richie
to the solution raising of so many names
for things on transportation and we
didn't get discussed it for we went live
I'm gonna leave it open is just
transportation in general because it
could be goods or it could be people so
for the first 15 minutes he will be
talking about what we currently do for
transportation both ourselves and the
world right what we think is good about
it what we think is bad about it and the
reason we only get 15 minutes is this is
generally what we concentrate on mostly
in society so we're just kind of
rehashing things that we've probably
talked about a lot or thought about a
lot even if you haven't necessarily
thought about transportation in general
so whoever would like to start can share
some thoughts on what you currently do
for transportation well do you need we
need a certain amount of courage those
of us who are unprepared I can always
start well if you want to start that's
fine if you want a fool to jump in where
angels fear to tread I'm willing to be
the fool all right let's do that I would
love to hear your thoughts Lisa okay
well I've been working with disaster
recovery I live in Northern California
and as you may know we've had a number
of fires which Psygnosis Richie you had
in Australia as well and one of the big
transportation problems that we've had
has been transportation of goods
especially goods which volunteers want
to give to disaster victims disaster
survivors victims is not politically
correct but we've had a tremendous
outpouring from private individuals who
want to clean their closets and some of
them want to give away their racks but
others want to give away really valuable
clothing to people that have been wiped
out
so there's clothing there's furniture
there's household supplies there's
consumables there's food and often these
are coming from out of the area actually
we got a shipment of I forgotten where
the zero goes either ten thousand or a
hundred thousand two
bulbs that were sent to the campfire in
Northern California to replant after the
fire which was a wonderful contribution
but it's the content it's the
transportation when things are going
from one person to another that was a
real problem and it seemed to me and
this is a sort of unvetted opinion that
what happened was the the agencies that
were trying to organize relief for the
people impacted by the disasters
negatively impacted was that they felt
like they have to be the storage depot
for all the donations so transportation
was put first
which meant well first was somebody said
I want to give a closet full of little
children's clothes but I can't get them
there so you have to arrange for
transportation but but along with
transportation is inventory or storage
which is the the one end of
transportation and it seems like a lot
of the agencies that wanted to be
helping agencies didn't understand the
logistics of just-in-time delivery and
so I was advocating rather than put
transportation the goods are made are
available at one source then immediately
you want to transport transport them
then you have to warehouse them then you
have to distribute them was to do a much
more just-in-time kind of process where
what the the agencies did was they
handled putting the donor and the
recipient together so that they could
make their own arrangements for how they
the goods got transported and it might
be that you needed a third donor who
would be someone who would donate the
transportation whether they would donate
the funds for commercial shipping or
whether they would
what a dining room full of furniture and
their pickup and drive it to the
recipient I just think we could do with
local transportation we could do a lot
more with volunteer with donation with
doing not doing mass transportation of
the goods but doing individual
transportation and not necessarily using
commercial shipping so that's just one
idea to throw out and I don't know if
it's on topic or not yes I think there's
perfectly on topic you guys can hear me
right I just switched to the different
it's like it there's a weird buzz in the
room more here so Richie do you want to
share do want me to sure yeah sure sure
yeah so I mean the transportation that I
use is mainly buses and trains at the
moment I used to have a car and when I
was looking at New Zealand but I covered
in my car and yeah I'm sort of just
organizing my life around public
transport for the meantime partly
financially and partly just because you
know having a car as a pain in the ass
but I mean the the system works pretty
well here locally in Melbourne like
having your transportation connected
with Google Maps it's just fantastic
really easy to get around I mean buses
are late in Italy every so often but
it's generally a pretty reliable system
especially given how huge the city is
but yeah what was the other part of the
question
it's just what you're currently doing
for transportation or like Lisa talked
about transportation of goods what this
what's currently happening in the world
and what's good and bad about it yeah
well yes of my personal trends yeah yeah
my personal transportation is pretty
effective for the users that I have
designed myself around the systems that
are already there I think they're pretty
good
I think traffic's probably quite a
nightmare so you know it would be good
to see in the future less cars on the
road more you know ride-sharing more
those sorts of being able to just nobody
owns a
I just you know you just hire that when
you need it that kind of thing but I
don't know if we can sort of figure out
those systems and then the wider
transportation system I'm not very
familiar with thanks for chief UM
transportation something are given some
thought to but it's not definitely one
of my areas of expertise but I
personally have a vehicle in Vancouver
we have amazing public transit the
public transit doesn't work for me
doesn't work with having a kid and
getting from door to door not with my
disability so because I don't have
enough money to drive an electric car I
end up buying like a $5,000 car and ends
up lasted about five years and run it
into the ground then get a new one and
it's it doesn't feel good as an
environmentalist to be doing it that way
but it seems to be what's effective for
my life I take a plane every four or
five years to go visit family actually
I'm visiting family right now and it's
the coronavirus and possibly going back
to that Cooper early but the the cost as
well as of course the environmental cost
of plane travel is not sustainable and
the I know with the transportation of
goods it seems ridiculous that we like
mine take the raw resources from one
country and ship them to somewhere to
get to get manufactured ship them
somewhere else to get used and ship them
back to get recycled or disposed of and
a lot of times it just makes no sense
it's like traveling back and forth
across the globe several times and we're
not making stuff to last which is not
this conversation or talking about
transportation but that that is all in
embedded in the good that it's not
designed to last and it's designed to be
shipped all over the world so it's made
in one location which is very fragile
it's very right now we're seeing that
with with what's going on in the world
that if something is only made in one
location what do you do and they can't
make it especially if it's something
that is is life-saving and and very much
needed like I know I supposedly the from
the Joe Rogan podcast all of the
dirtbags well can't think Ivy banks are
made in the Dominican Republic and so if
there was something that wiped it out
there's nothing like there's nowhere
else that makes them and I don't know
that was again was just on the children
podcast we have the doctor on talking
about the pandemic and that is basically
what I have to say about transportation
right now and so now we can switch on to
the next piece if or if anyone else has
anything to add for this one which is
what is currently going on well I think
I think one of the things we need to
specify is what it is that we're
transporting where we're living in the
age of information and I happen to be an
educator so one of the things I'm really
interested in is it when do we need to
transport people and when can we
transport bits because so much of what
we do is information and so we're having
a meeting here and we're transporting
bits we didn't have to transport the
people and we're spread all over the
place I don't know where you are to ibly
now isn't in your family but I'm in
Northern California and Richie you're in
melbourne australia melbourne australia
and we can have a very successful
meeting without transporting people on
the other hand there are huge numbers of
things that can't be done without
physical transportation of material
things whether they are live things or
inanimate objects so in some sense is to
really address this question of
transportation it's I think it's
important to ask the question could this
be done with the transportation of bits
are we are we talking about transporting
something that's basically informational
transporting something that's physical
you know and you can't hug each other
you don't transport the people but on
the other hand at this point we're
supposed to be isolating so this is the
best we can do but it's really important
because we're now faced with some
practical issues about online education
where we're not physically transporting
the books the papers were the people
we're doing it all digital this could be
a permanent you know way of being for
humans now because they reckon that you
know they're not going to get past like
we there is a potential that we might
not get past this particular virus so
there's a chance that we're always going
to have to make sure that we have some
level of social distancing and ramp it
up you know wind when necessary so that
we know it doesn't really begin which is
just a terrifying situation because
although this is a really good form of
communication it's not being in-person
face-to-face being up to hug one another
being in one another's presence so this
could be a big shift but it's not really
about transit not have a conversation
these days that doesn't bring epidemic
rotavirus in it it's our new world yeah
yeah well I mean yeah brings up a lot of
questions but how do we I mean in
transportation that is another piece
that is big is our global movement of
people brings with it the risk of
pandemic that people can be in China one
day and in California the next day and
in Paris the next day because they have
a jet-setting lifestyle causes this and
so if we're able to have a world where
if this is our new normal people need to
isolate for two weeks every time they
got off of any flight ever which means
you're gonna really have a higher metric
for am I gonna go visit right am I gonna
take two weeks at the end in order to to
make sure everybody's safe and having
maybe we don't socially distance and
stop hugging each other but we have
smaller communities but again not
transportations well it is in this if
you think of one of the parameters of
transportation as to how far you
transport something whether it's a
person who are good if we had local
communities where we knew that and let's
let's play with your hypothesis that we
continue to have pandemic like
infections that we have to limit one can
develop small local communities that are
isolated so that you can have a human
contact you can transport very locally
but you don't transport globally
without serious precautions so that's
something we might have to reorganize
yeah
and what are the other things that comes
to mind is also just of like the the non
fragilities well the nine things that
can cause chaos to disrupt the system
like we should be we should be preparing
for these well in advance anyway because
we knew pennant pandemics were going to
be an issue that was gonna crop up at
some point in time and you know that the
way that we've handled it you know as
governments and institutions hasn't
really didn't I mean I'm sure it's good
given the circumstances but you know as
a society we're just not aware of it and
we haven't sort of like this issue about
how City sorry I'm kind of derailing
this but like my tenure of my general
point is that you know systems like
Transport are affected by you know these
these massive events and then how can we
like I feel like going the local is a
great place to go because that way we
have more robustness in the face of go
do what you need to do Richie I can drop
you out just okay okay that's better
that way he can them come back on camera
when he back up so he can continue on
without him so we can shift into the
next piece which is what does your they
don't need to match we don't need to
okay imma chronically agree on our
vision of the future but what is your
perfect world look like for
transportation 5 10 100 years out
however long you need it to be out in
order for it to be possible in your life
from my perspective
again the parameters are really
important what you transporting and how
far you're transporting it so I've
already made two points one is we should
be looking at when we can do transport
digitally when we can use our digital
platforms to more carefully deal with
the physical transportation problem and
uber and lyft are good examples of
new ways of handling transportation and
so ideally we would use all the tools
that we have developed in the last 20
years to manage our transportation
systems better and we would also
understand the the value of functioning
locally it's almost like we've been in
thrall of the potential of global travel
and so we've been experimenting for a
couple hundred years with all the things
we can do with global travel and now
that we've explored that and you know
that we can do lots of very exciting
wonderful things with global travel now
we're in a kind of evaluative phase so I
see the future as us really looking at
the actions that our modern technologies
have enabled and deciding which ones we
want to use and how we want to use them
what and we're looking at one of the
negative consequences of this wonderful
global travel and we don't want to throw
the baby out with the bathwater by
throwing out all of global travel but a
lot of careful thought needs to go into
when do we need to manufacture locally
when do we need and therefore transport
locally when do we need to what's the
carbon footprint of transporting so
that's the the global warming is one
negative consequences of having
exploited all the transportation
technologies that we have and we really
need to sit back and evaluate which ones
are worth continuing with and which ones
are worth getting rid of right yeah
those are all very good points
my ideal version of transportation in
the future it's weird because here you
talk I was like right this one piece I
don't know if I want it anymore which is
rapid rail trap
trouble right being able to get from
California to New York in a few hours on
the ground I do think it's somewhat more
safe because you don't have the recycled
air but the speed of it is the problem
but it's also what connects us and what
makes it helpful I don't know if I
needed you Richie so many of you excited
off you can invite me to jihad and but
having the ability to get somewhere
without taking off and landing and
possibly having big ships they transport
across the the Atlantic or having
massive rail that goes underwater or
overwater I don't know what that is but
have you noticed sorry
through tunnels through tunnels yeah
having it be the ability to actually
have massive what I would like
personally is I would like to have
access to a car I would like it to be
autonomous I would like it to drive me
somewhere and I would like to say where
I need to get picked up and dropped off
and I don't care if there's somebody
else in that car with me but I want to
be able to get dropped off from point A
to point B also be able to state whether
it's within like whether someone's been
wearing perfume whether it has a dog in
it like having make sure that it's
diverse that there's a vehicle that
everyone can use and then I can get
stuff done in the car if I need to and
then also what you had had stay at leas
that's a very good point making sure
that whatever can be done in bits is
done in bits that being able to live in
a local community as is part of what I
would love to have in the future and I
would like to live there and spend 99
percent of my time there and incept when
I go and visit family or family come to
visits me but I want to connect it to
the globe in talking and I want to be
able to solve problems together and have
deep discussions on things that interest
me and if my community doesn't talk
about the things I want to talk about I
want to be able to find people around
the globe and that's the kind of thing
that that I can do online and I think
that the more we start I don't know the
word is propping up we'd like your
looked at is affluence and privileged if
you're able to travel around the globe
that you've like been to Paris you've
been to Russia that you've been to
Africa and if that's no longer the case
and instead it's like listen I
experienced Paris in VR I experienced
walking up Kilimanjaro in the simulation
it's a we don't need to all trace about
the globe and I can still feel like I
had that experience because it's not
about whether or not I'm better than
someone else it's just about do I feel
like I had that experience then someone
else like where I would really like to
go in person because my grandmother's
been there my sister's been there as
Machu Picchu and so there are some that
I would put at a higher level that are
like no I really want to physically go
there Paris though where I could like
mute the sound and walk through the
streets thank you VR would be perfect be
able to go to the museum's and feel like
you're right there in front of it you
have you know the whole the whole Louvre
to yourself and you can look around or
you can add the people whatever whatever
it makes sense to use so that is what a
bit of my oh and one more thing which
was that when we owned cars together
they're designed to be to last where
like you the engine's easy to be put in
and take it out if it's an engine I just
said electric cars but like that that
type of work they're designed to last
and the components to be replaced it's
my version of an ideal future I would
like to to live in how about you Richie
welcome back yeah I've been like I think
transportation isn't really an issue if
you know we don't have too much
transportation on the road and it's not
like the way that we power it isn't
negative to our environment so if you've
got electric cars that are powered on
fusion reactors like like not fusion
reactions within the car but like you
know it's not fossil fuels that we're
burning in order to fuel to her power
that thing then you know we can have as
much transportation as we like and you
know if we can recycle old vehicles and
turn them into new vehicles if that if
there's a way to do that economically
then we should do that but I mean really
this for me the soy just comes back down
to things need to change like on the
individual level in the community level
like we just need it need a different
philosophy of how we're going to
organize ourselves within society
because you know just you know
manufacturing new cars and having to
have like the like having to be able to
sell you know a million cars in order to
prototype the next car or like those
kinds of things like it's just such a
waste like it's so much so much
resources that we're just throwing away
and maybe we can do it over you know 300
400 years
but like what is what is the resource
cycle for all of those components like
like fossil fuel the the resource cycle
is so long so you can't really you know
use use that stuff and then reuse it
again in you know 50 years or something
it takes a long time to be for that to
be reusable so yeah new things to change
but yeah
electric cars shared electric cars with
like specific you know scenes and spaces
and those those kinds of things that
sounds great and Leslie the lease people
who are stuck in traffic for you know X
amount of time in their lives the better
because that's just you know really
ditch when we do it for people I think
yeah I think like if life looked like it
looks now where people are living in
suburbs and driving into the city be
able to connect cars together where they
were able to be more efficient and then
you know and they communicate with each
other to see they knew where one was
getting off so it could be faster but
also I don't want to live in a suburb
and drive into the city I want to live
in my community I want to like work
online with people around the world and
I want to play music and eat and connect
and you know raise our kids with a small
community that we walk in
maybe bike you know like that that's
even doable and be surrounded by nature
and spend most of my time in that
community in the surrounding area is
what I would prefer but other people
prefer to live in the city and I want
people to have diversity well that's
what I had the privilege of doing so
come come to Northern California yeah
actually no it won't be rural if too
many people come I wanted to just
mention an invention that I worked on a
couple of years ago several years ago
now but which was I got through the idea
stage we never built a prototype but it
would be a personal transportation pod
which would be like the interior of a
small car a to earth two-person car
which is what you owned and then you
could attach that to what's called a
truck which is like the wheels the the
bottom that it could either go into an
onto an individual
or it could go onto a train or it could
go onto an air vehicle or it could go
onto a boat so that you didn't it was
not a single purpose transportation
vehicle and it should be comfortable
enough so that you might want to use it
for your office as well and so that that
kind of piggybacks on your idea of well
they should attach together because you
could put it on a connected train that
runs on the road as compared with a
train that runs on a track but you could
do either if you had the transportation
pod so I don't know if anybody's working
on that or not but it's an idea that I'm
perfectly willing to throw out into the
universe and see if anybody else - it's
a cool idea I like it um like it doesn't
affect you I also wanted to bring up
although it's not directly related to
transportation is related to not
transporting goods
James Jones's project cube spawn of
having a locally sourced way to
manufacture basically anything further
where it's like a Lego effect it's like
a Lego factory like the factory itself
is Lego where you can put these pieces
together and have it work through and be
able to move around and create different
things for different people it's like a
3d printer but much much more complex
and I think having one of those in every
community so that you can print it there
and manufactured there and manufactured
and the quantity wants and need as
opposed to having it be be shipped and
then we can have some things that don't
make sense you need that way made more
redundant so that you aren't having that
that fragility but have you know at
least two factories in the world making
it but have it shipped when for things
that are that makes sense to you so
mm-hmm it's kind of like every every
community needs its own maker space
which has industrials quality tools that
anybody can eat it so that you can do
that local manufacture our libraries are
beginning here in California to be
turned into maker spaces as well so we
not only have books that can be borrowed
but also welders that can be bought
borrowed and an auto shop that can be
bought borrowed and a surge sewing
machine that can be borrowed yeah nice
and even for those like we have to a
library's in Vancouver I don't have as
one here in Edmonton but having the
barrier of not having your own personal
vehicle having it be able to be
delivered having that you can get a
sewing machine and have it dropped off
to you and picked up to you and the more
were able I on this thing in my head
called the hub I was calling him her
every person it was like an alternative
to Amazon where you could bake cookies
in your house and Silva or you know jam
or crafts of any kind in every every
everyday or at once a week depending on
the threshold of people you had a pickup
in a drop-off so whatever you made was
picked up and given to it brought back
to the hub and then just first to the to
the customers or other members I don't
like their customers and then you got a
delivery and a pickup is the point so
you could it was a lot easier if you had
an adventure you don't have to figure
out how to get it to person and things
like to libraries and goods libraries
could also be used in that way where hey
my friend has a book across town and
said a meeting to go pick it up
I just know she'll put it in her next
delivery and it will make it to me again
this is sort of a supply chain
management which is what's behind
transportation and then since you
mentioned baking cookies at home another
issue that has to be dealt with is all
the regulation which is although it's
not transportation in the sense that
it's not a car or a train or a truck or
an airplane it is we do have to when we
discuss transportation we have to look
at all of the regulations that make it
possible to transport and have everybody
participate in in a coordinated system
so along with the discussion about
transportation of people in material
things to talk about the regulations
around that and how to govern it yeah I
was like allowed to sell the cookies
that
baked in your own kitchen yeah I know
you would leave allowed to give them
away why Mike if it's just I'm gonna
bake them and I'm who wants them and
then I'm giving them ways that different
regulations and if we want to bake mass
amounts of cookies do we need a
commercial kitchen and then how do we
coordinate that and so well that's not
transportation as you said it is the
system that's going to be using the
transportation and how efficiently we
can do we can do all of it
yeah consumer whatever that word is in a
better world and a maker a maker and a
user right of various various goods and
services and that like although that's
not transportation being able to have
like a hair dress or come to your
community as opposed to everyone going
out to the hairdresser having um I mean
if you're in a 300 person community you
probably have a hairdresser there but
having a massage therapist come out
having someone come out that is they're
traveling to you one time and they're
it's much more efficient for them
because they're seen one person after
another
clearly not during this time period and
then um yeah that transporting one
person as opposed to a bunch of people
it's not bits but it's more efficient
mm-hmm okay so we're at the 30 minute
mark so now we get to transfer over to
the other unless someone has closing
statements which lets us that first does
anybody have any closing statements for
a world they would like to create its
contingent on a lot of different things
yeah but now we're gonna get to that
like tangent the adjacent possible so
now we're gonna talk about what could we
do with 10,000 people and hundred
thousand dollars that could either be a
global 10,000 people to something like a
nap or I don't know what that would look
like for transportation or it could be a
local 10,000 right 10,000 in Vancouver
10,000 in Northern California 10,000 in
Sydney a bigger in Melbourne actually
aren't you 10,000 a Melbourne like
having an but just that metric because
that's a that's a doable thing it's
something that you're on I mean isn't
let's redesign our entire transportation
system what
we actually do with 10,000 people and
$100,000 well we certainly have the
example of the rideshare services and in
a lot of senses we not only are talking
about the transportation of goods we're
also talking about the transportation of
services so moving and this has been
going on for 30 40 years is trying to
conceptualize to think about what used
to be thought of as a product a physical
product that got sold as a service
that's being sold and of course their
paradigmatic example is flooring is
carpeting services so instead of selling
carpets you sell carpeting services in a
company that sells them handles the
transportation the manufacturer the
transportation the installation and the
removal and end of product life
recycling so they've sold us the service
of carpeting rather than the carpet and
you could think about that in terms well
here addressing you could think about
that in terms of taxi service which has
always been a service but you can think
of the taxi or you can think of the taxi
service so in some senses its
specifically in transportation that
experiments been done with uber and lyft
and the other ride-sharing services and
now you've talked about the hub concept
we're doing that with with home produced
services going to a hub and coming back
and those are all things you can do
thing you can do lots and lots of stuff
with with at the scale that you're
talking about which is you said ten
thousand people in a hundred thousand
yeah yeah there are tons of
possibilities and that's why we're doing
this process it's not just to pick one
it's to kind of just generate all of the
possibilities we could do with
transportation and then when our next
step when we figured this out a while
then we can pick one and actually make
it together find 10,000 people each put
in ten bucks and actually make it but
right now it's yeah because I think that
creating a cooperatively owned upper or
left where the drivers are looked after
and as the user we can problem solve
together to make it more efficient so I
can't afford lyft and uber but I might
be able to cart a crowd to share a car
with let's new right if I'm coming home
from a concert instead of it being surge
pricing be like okay well if we're able
to be connected on app and it could say
hey four of us are going home together
and so it's gonna be one third of the
price the drivers gonna make more but
we're all gonna pay less again clearly
not in this climate but like those kind
of solutions when we figured out the
tactic so not only do you have to have
the platform for the contacting the
driver and getting the driver to the
customer but the customer cohort has to
be able to get in touch with each other
so that if I'm at this San Francisco
Symphony and I need a ride back to Santa
Rosa California I can find I can query
the crowd at the symphony and find out
if there's anybody else that wants to go
back to Santa Rosa and and as you said
and then we could ride share together
it's hard to find each other right I was
envisioning more that it would be behind
the scenes hey by the way Lisa we know
that you have a neighbor going there
would you be okay riding with them and
you would say yes or no and they would
say yes or no if you both said yes you'd
get matched up well they're actually our
places in San Francisco that our carpool
stops and you can go and stand at the
carpool stop and see if anybody stops by
who's going close to where you need to
go I haven't used one but it seemed like
I thought it was a good enough idea
sorry for the sign which is essentially
it sounds like hitchhiking right which
is like illegal everywhere but like
because it's car shared and there's a
spot it's more there's a safety feature
to that but there's a safety we can
build into an app more easily it's not
100% of course but something that could
be how do I trust you whether you're the
driver or the passenger how do we share
in gas how do I know that you might get
me to point B
I need to get to point C's there's
someone else going there afterwards
right and so being able to coordinate
basically hitchhiking along I in Canada
our Greyhound our busses quit they no
longer and not because the quantifiers
they quit like over a year ago because
they couldn't get little places and it's
only the big like out east is still
where it's still operating between
Toronto and Ottawa and Montreal but not
out here I couldn't even make it home
from here if the planes got grounded
because there's no bus between I'm sure
there is actually about so there's in
the Greyhound isn't the one that was
there but these these other ride-sharing
apps could could take the place and then
also in cities more like uber and lyft
where we're also looking after I don't
know if we could do with a hundred
thousand dollars but finding mechanics
who can service the vehicles at cost
right so that there a lot of the money
that uber drivers may go to the
maintenance of their vehicles having gas
be made more cheap maybe they don't have
as many taxes because for ricard sharing
and to be those things but again I don't
know if that's doable four hundred
thousand dollars so for 10,000 people
and $100,000 car sharing and an app for
car sharing you couldn't create well
these are all experiments that can be
tried and there is there's a group
called Code for America which actually
is a bunch of techies who are willing to
write apps for free so you probably
could do it for a hundred thousand
dollars we use Code for America a local
Code for America group but there's an
awful lot that we could do if
essentially we have a huge amount of
leisure time we've been spent the last
five hundred years developing
labor-saving devices and they do save a
lot of labor we don't have to scrub our
front door suits anymore and we can just
vacuum off and they're pretty clean you
have huge amounts of leisure time but we
haven't figured out is how to share it
and so part of what we're talking about
well ostensibly we're talking about
transportation we're talking about the
sharing of transportation
and that's how you get to do to service
10,000 people for much less money than
if you had to buy every piece of it it's
funny you saying that uh hitchhiking is
illegal because that's like the standard
in New Zealand that's this how everyone
gets around just perfect it's kind of
weird that it's illegal because it's
there's much more unsafe things it's
been hitchhiking at the same time it's
unsafe you don't know the person but a
lot of when we design apps together we
design technology together I think
that's something we can discuss and
implement safety that isn't creepy right
that isn't necessarily like ubers
telling you whether you're a good person
or not a good person and then you sue
uber if the person's not good right it's
like how do I know that I'm safe maybe I
just could request female drivers and I
only ride with people they're females
that's a little bit safer or someone who
has a long track record but having that
that not peaceful into it which again
isn't quite transportation but it's
needed for transportation well it's also
um from what a consequence of the change
in transportation because I look at the
three of us I'm two generations older
than you guys and hitchhiking was legal
and was normal I grew up in
Massachusetts when I was a kid and
everybody did it it was a much safer
society however it was also a society
where there was less transportation
available and so not only was it harder
for the good guys to get around it was
harder for the bad guys to get around
and again they were there there are
positive and negatives to the increase
of transportation of people and our our
ability to move around has in some ways
made the boundaries of our individual
communities so much more open and
flexible that we don't feel safe in the
same way we don't protect each other I
mean we never we didn't take the keys
out of our car
when I was a kid and we never locked the
door that was unheard of and your
friends would walk in and say hello
anybody there but the idea of locking
the door was was strange so I don't know
if it's in a sense that's not that's not
transportation and yet it's a
consequence a lot of the change in
transportation yeah absolutely I think
one of the things we could do at 10,000
people in $100,000 is map at least a
part of our supply chain is like where
did this pen come from where did maybe I
will never know that but if I can break
down that there's aluminum in it what
how much where is aluminum made in the
world right maybe it doesn't know where
the aluminum in this pen came from but
it can average all the aluminum that's
made and where it was made and here's
the transportation for it because it's
it's math plus data if we have it and
then from there we can have a lot more
power in our supply chain we can see the
fragility of it on the transportation of
good and we can see where well would it
make sense to produce pence locally
there how much they probably wouldn't be
cheaper but what level would we need to
make them at for them to be cheaper they
should be if it's not using a lot of
labor for them to be made locally versus
made somewhere else and shipped here I
mentioned that daughter is out there
already that's kind of goes back to the
you know how many slaves work for you
because eventually those supply chains
generally lead to you know horrible
conditions but yeah it's an easier way
to do things because I I think like
different materials cluster in different
parts of the world unevenly well and
also if you if you make a commitment to
local manufacturer you may also make a
commitment to changing the materials
that you're using so that you're using
local materials I mean we could use
goose quills we've got we got plenty of
turkeys here and plenty of turkey
feathers while turkeys are typically
and there used to be a pencil factory
right down the street it might be that
we would use pencils rather than or
pointing fence more if we had a
commitment to local manufacture so it
things are all connected together or not
if you change one thing if you set up a
principle that says we don't want to
transport things as much things new
technologies and new products made from
different you know we'll eat more local
eggs and chickens and less
much of this changes if we start pricing
at extra externalities because like the
price of you know what someone should be
making for whatever job that is that
they're doing and then the cost of the
transportation to get from you know one
side of the world to the other like we
should be pricing the stuff and so that
we don't have to create the illusion
that it's cheaper to make things
elsewhere because that's kind of what
the tout works in our current economic
model but that's not how works in terms
of like the price of you know destroying
the environment or whatever it is or
eroding communities or taking away
opportunities with people and the local
you're right
I don't think we could get rid of
externalities but 10,000 people hundred
thousand dollars it might be a great a
system that shows you the externalities
right so although I paid two bucks for
this pen it should have been twenty
right and so I at least know that if I
want to and look it up um and and
knowing right that like okay you bought
the eggs that were 50% less that the
health care and the chickens life and
all this stuff on top of it is and you
can even see it broken down that might
be something that we could do for
$100,000 so that the 10,000 people have
access to their top goods right there
most of the food they buy most of the
clothes they buy most the makeup and
household goods
what is the externality or just how do
we make it better
Harry do you guys have go local
initiatives in your communities we don't
in Sonoma County California there's a I
think it's the supervisors I'm not sure
who it is who
done it or the chambers of commerce have
a whole campaign which is called go
local and companies local companies
advertised that this product was
produced locally and many stores give a
discount if you buy the local product so
it's a it's a combination of the actual
economics of it and the kind of ethics
of it and something to view the campaign
but part of the goal local initiative is
to as you said bring bring to attention
the travel the transportation costs of
the goods and the local by local it
really addresses that now I suspect that
more than ten thousand dollars was
invested in it but it might not have
been more than ten thousand dollars a
year yeah I mentioned like eighty
thousand of that hundred thousand would
just be advertising if what you're doing
is a campaign yes if your objective is
to raise people's awareness and change
their behavior because they've got
different information yeah that's
advertising or information dissemination
yeah and then maybe this is like a bit
of way to do things because if we if we
started local communities maybe the
focus of those local communities would
be more unlike what is the system that
you're actually embedded in and like
what are the things that are going a lot
around that are actually pushing things
towards you know business solutions
better organization those kinds of
things so people don't have to spend
crazy amounts of money on advertising
and they're just you know people they're
just aware of it because it's part of
the local community it's again it's kind
of different but I think like all of the
stuff I feel like we just need a
different approach on other levels like
if we solve problems that are a little
at a lower level then we can like these
things just become easier to solve but
yeah I think wonderful though again it's
not transportation itself but it's
transportation adjacent is picking an
industry like clothing that is
definitely made of somewhere
and the stuffs brought brought somewhere
and made and then shipped of like how
can we design clothing swaps to be more
easy or shared closets so that if I'm
going to a special events I can borrow
somebody else's and you can exchange
them or having a tool library even if
you're not in a big city center anyone
and I know these things already exist
but if they exist when we create them
together they're much more useful um
like you have a power drill I can borrow
as opposing to it needing to be in a
central database that I can borrow it
from then I can just borrow it directly
from you and it helps us figure out
where the stuff is so that it doesn't
need to be transported but it could
maybe be transported with the hub light
I think the hub could be set up in the
city for a hundred thousand dollars by
finding a bunch of local businesses that
do want their goods to be to be
delivered and already have them under
the regulations and then figuring out
how do we work together to get them to
your customer first cheap as possible as
ethically as possible and then other
people can come on board as they have
goods and services and have one one hub
location it probably couldn't be served
for hundred thousand dollars in
Vancouver but a more rural place it
could be less expensive places need to
grow so is there a difference between
that and setting up a a barter system
and in a sense a barter system if you
set up a barter exchange platform and
give everybody mm-hmm
five hundred or a thousand dollars
credit to prime that pump and then
everybody lists the services that they
have to offer or the products they have
to offer and then you just press the Go
button and let it let it run I mean that
we can certainly do with $100,000 you
could probably do that with $10,000 yeah
I mean that a shirt is different than
the barter system but that also sounds
like a viable a very amazing option to
have on the table or creating am
a barter of goods and services that then
you don't have to transport you're not
having all of the bureaucracy involved
in everything everything you do together
or listen to say socially I think just
doing it for free right like I said
about the cookies like here's what
here's what I'm giving and I'm giving it
to the to the world who needs it the
most
and having multiple options people who
need to make money and people who see
which one which one plays out which one
calls the most people in suppose you
could have also have an app where you
look like so someone's at their house
and they're like I need a you know a
toast or something like that and that
creates another thing and they seemed
out of thinking sort of like how the
rideshare apps work and then if
someone's traveling you know pass them
at some point that could be like oh I
don't know am I using my toaster at the
moment I'm going to be leaving in five
minutes so you can like yeah I guess the
problem with that is just the attention
economy because you're gonna have to
somehow get people's attention people
gonna have to put this thing on and like
what series do that probably none there
was this um Facebook group called mums
to moms that I was part of and it was
like you'd put something up for free it
was always for free you'd be like I have
a guitar and then there'd be a bunch of
people and if you could have a either
first come first serve you could do like
a lottery system and I was disappointed
because I gave my guitar to it and then
later on it was like wait I actually
want my guitar and it could end so
you're allowed to say what you wanted
and if it was something that came up
then you were the first to get it and it
was the only thing I put I was like I
want a guitar and someone came up with a
guitar and they were like oh Jubilee
wants a guitar they were like no no you
can't want a guitar it's not like a
needed item so we're gonna auction it it
was like that's not and so having
something like that system but when you
gave something you were just as likely
to get that same thing back so I didn't
need to hold on to it right like if I
gave you the guitar I would get a guitar
later if I wanted one and then you'd be
more willing to give it up right be like
if I want this book back honestly this
one like any one of that book then I'll
get it if I want it so I can be more
willing to give it out submit its lens
everywhere and it just it just keeps
what I've given into the system so that
I again
I couldn't get a guitar back is that the
difference between a donating system and
a lending system if you if if they
wanted a guitar and somebody and you
could lend your guitar then the
recipient could keep it until you wanted
it back and then I had it back but it
work it's working system you can't get
it back yeah yeah so you could start it
you could set up the platform so that
you could specify whether it was a loan
or a donation it's just another bit in
the database yeah with with a toaster
there's some issue because it's a
there's a hygiene issue around whether
you get your toaster back clean or
filled with somebody else's crumbs so in
current lending like lending tool
lending library kinds of things often
you have to put a cleaning deposit down
so that if you don't give it back clean
it can be somebody gets paid yeah but
that's that's the little hurdle that
could be solved as compared with the
basic idea yeah plus things cuz I'm not
the cleanest person so like I want
someone to know that when they're
lending me something and I will try I
will clean it but it probably won't come
back pristine there's other people I
know don't probably come back better
than you lent it to them because they're
just the kind of people who know how to
get every mark off of stuff but having
that right not a rating like you're not
going to give it to me so I'm still
gonna look after to the best of my
ability or if you have a cat or a dog
and then you're allergic maybe you don't
lend it to somebody with that just
having more information in the systems
you can be more focused on it and if
everything I borrow breaks you know
maybe I stop borrowing stuff but you see
who is the person who doesn't clean
stuff or break stuff and and maybe they
you know to know the risk associated
with lending a specific person something
yeah well the thing is the more the more
bad actors there are in a system the
least likely to continue to use them so
yeah but that's like I'm not a bad like
I don't think I'm a bad actor but like
if you just have that information right
like okay you you are gonna forget you
haven't forget to give it back right
like we're all different you Minh beings
with our own failings so just knowing if
this is the height because everyone
can't be perfect in fact nobody's
perfect so we all probably have things
that we don't do but knowing what thing
you don't do that it's going to annoy me
at the highest level so I don't gift it
to like I don't lend it to that person
maybe I only gift it to that person
right so that I know it's okay I'm never
gonna get it back it's never gonna be in
that stage it's like friends I have who
I know are late all the time but I know
they're late all the time so I'd give
that that extra that extra time and send
it back half an hour well they don't
think they're bad people
as as these platforms get designed we
have to it's an iterative process where
you design it and you try it out and
this problem comes up we can anticipate
a couple of the problems but we probably
can't anticipate them all we have to try
it out and part of I think being
successful is a matter of being flexible
and whether it's we just we just in
Sonoma County California started the
smart train which is a light rail that
goes doesn't go all the way to San
Francisco but it goes close and some of
the some of the features that were
implemented were successful and some of
them are not and there there was just in
the primary we just had to vote on
whether to continue to fund the smart
train and a lot of people were saying
well it didn't meet their expectations
so therefore we shouldn't keep it going
and other people are saying hey this is
a continuous approved but projects and
we need to keep funding it and it will
get better so thinking that the our
first answer is the definitive answer in
anything but trans certainly in
transportation is probably not going to
evolve a very successful transfer
transportation system over time or board
of sight more linda's and I think that's
an important part of anything we create
is that it doesn't need to be perfect
it's start
somewhere and then it it improves and
gets better as you have more people I
mean the idea also have been 10,000
people creating a solution is that
hopefully they have some ownership over
that solutions they're more likely to
accept slightly subpar and they're more
likely to give their contribution both
idea and financial to help improve it
because they feel ownership over it so
that is very much in alignment with I
think anything we create together is
what's the easiest thing or the simplest
or the the best the thing that's gonna
have the most impact for the least
amount of money to be created and then
how do we look for what's going wrong
and continually improve it for their
maximum benefit does anyone have
anything else they would like to add
we're getting up to the hour so I can
give our closing statements nothing it
was good I'm okay I'm just delighted to
participate because I this is my first
time to find out about this activity and
I'd love to be involved with further
solution rising yeah absolutely I would
love to have you again these that is
Frank meeting you and so we can say
goodbye to the online world and then we
can go out the world and chat a bit so
thank you everyone who was here and
tuned in or people watching this summer